Finding Aid for Fred Stanley Goodrich Papers, 1863-1918
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred Stanley Goodrich papers 1863-1918
Goodrich, Fred Stanley, 1836-1919.
0.3 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder
85170 Aa 2; UAm
Alpena, Michigan, resident. Correspondence, including a letter from Thomas Wentworth Higginson and a letter describing Goodrich's Civil War experience in the 115th New York Volunteers at the Battle of Morris Island, South Carolina, genealogical material, recipe book, and miscellanea; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Marjory H. Drake (donor no. 2940 ).
The collection is open to research.
Fred S. Goodrich was a civil war soldier with the 115th New York Volunteers who later transferred to the 33rd United States Colored Troops where he served until the end of the war.. After the war, he lived in Alpena, Michigan from 1871 to 1882 where sold watches, clocks, and jewelry. In 1882, he moved to De Land, Florida in 1882. He was elected mayor of De Land for five terms. He ran for US Congress as a Republican in 1888 but was defeated. He also lived and worked in the Oklahoma Territory.
Fred Stanley Goodrich papers consist of correspondence, including a letter from Thomas Wentworth Higginson and a letter describing Goodrich's Civil War experience in the 115th New York Volunteers at the Battle of Morris Island, South Carolina, genealogical material, recipe book, miscellanea and individual and group photographs of Goodrich family members. The collection is noteworthy for a detailed description of the Battle of Morris Island in South Carolina during the summer of 1863.
Subjects:
Cookery.; Goodrich family.; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 115th (1862-1865); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Morris Island, Battle of, S.C., 1863 (July 10-September 7); Fort Wagner (S.C.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Alpena (Mich.); Florida.; Goodrich family.; Oklahoma.
Contributors:
Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal
  - Correspondence, undated, 1863, 1888-1918 and 1940 (Box 1)
    (include letter from Thomas Wentworth Higginson)
  - Biographical information, undated and 1916 of Fred S. Goodrich (Box 1)
  - Slave Songs of the United States. New YorkA Simpson and Co. 1867 (Box 1)
    (inscribed to Goodrich by T.W. Higginson)
- Family and miscellaneous
  - Genealogical records, 1896, 1905 and 1916 of Goodrich family (Box 1)
  - The Goodrich family in America edited by LaFayette Wallace Case ChicagoFergus Printing Company 1889 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, undated, 1897, 1918 and 1929 of Goodrich family members (Box 1)
  - Recipe book of Mrs. F. S. Goodrich (then living in the Oklahoma Territory), undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Goodrich family, individuals and groups (Box 1)
    (see also portrait of Fred Stanley Goodrich in oversize folder UAm)
  - Goodrich family, homes, stores, etc. (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Fred Stanley Goodrich (Folder UAm)
    (oversize folder UAm)